<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Edu | Jacob Fisher</title>
        <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/</link>
        <description>Latest blog posts from Edu | Jacob Fisher</description>

        
        <language>en-gb</language>
        

        

        

        
        <copyright>© MMXXI, Jacob Fisher</copyright>
        

        
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        

        
        <atom:link href="https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        

        
            
        <item>
          <title>Evaluate the environmental impact of extraction of raw materials in Nigeria</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/nigeria-raw-materials-extraction/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/nigeria-raw-materials-extraction/</guid>
          <description>(revisions in bold) Oil extraction can lead to oil spills which are highly damaging to local ecosystems, such as the Bodo oil spills between 2008-2009. Because of the hugely dense deposit of oil (11 million gallons across 20km²), it will take at least 30 years for the area’s ecosystem to regenerate.
The damage can be amplified in undersea oil pipelines and offshore oil pumps as special diving equipment or specialised for bigger oil spills, which take a long time to deploy and, therefore, to fix the oil spill.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Reducing the North-South divide</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/north-south-divide/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/north-south-divide/</guid>
          <description>(revisions in bold) The North-South divide is stark, yet the line seems impalpable to most everyone. Part of the reason for this is that the changes between the “north” and the “south” occur gradually — despite many trying to clearly define a line similar to Hadrian’s Wall. For example, around ¼ of people living in the Midlands say they consider themselves Northern, and only around 7.5% saying they consider themselves Southern.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>South-west Stonehenge &#34;super highway&#34;</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/a303/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/a303/</guid>
          <description>In 2017, Theresa May’s government announced plans to build a tunnel, at least 3.2km long, underneath Stonehenge, but 50m further away from the monument, although the first mention of a tunnel under Stonehenge came in 1995. This plan is a result of the £15 billion road improvement plan that Cameron’s government announced in 2014, under which the A303 was flagged requiring improvements. Prime Minister David Cameron said the road “held parts of the country back”.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Summary of the differences between the behaviour of the children at the two schools</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/english/p2/q2/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/english/p2/q2/</guid>
          <description>differing teaching attitudes differing attitudes from the children differing attitudes to education difference between surroundings and the school  In Source A, the attitudes to education are open, with a lot of emphasis on creativity. This can be inferred from the fact that “children’s painting[s] and poems […] covered every available space”, suggesting that the school embraced the children’s creativity. However, in the second source, the teacher remarks the schoolgirls are “boxing most viciously”, showing that the school is a place of violence rather than education.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Verdun assessment</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/history/verdun-assessment/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/history/verdun-assessment/</guid>
          <description>q. i) Write an account of how the Battle of Verdun became a crisis for both sides during 1916 (8 marks)
The Battle of Verdun became a crisis for the French as they had lost Fort Douaumont and their defensive positions at the start of the battle. Because it was seen as “the most well-defended city in France”, the French were reluctant to give it up, despite it having no major, strategic position.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Simon&#39;s significance in Golding&#39;s Lord of The Flies</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/english/lotf/simon/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/english/lotf/simon/</guid>
          <description>Simon is, perhaps, the only character in the novel to symbolise Golding’s piety following the horrors he faced during his time serving in the British Navy. Monteith cut almost references and symbolism of religion out of the original draft, being an agnostic himself. In the beginning of the book, Simon reaches up into the trees to feed the desperate littluns' hands below, ensuring they get “double handfuls”. Simon is, in this passage, physically higher than the greedy littluns, almost suggesting he is metaphorically higher, too.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Verdun</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/history/verdun/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/history/verdun/</guid>
          <description>The Germans had not launched a major offensive on the Western Front since November 1914. Thus enter Verdun: the longest, and amongst the bloodiest of The First World War, which ultimately saw Germany’s own plan massively backfire, whilst the Russian war machine was now in full swing, the British and French began an offensive at the Somme (involving the first ever use of tanks), and the Romanians (following two years of neutrality) sided with the Triple Entente.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Our data</title>
          <link>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/fieldwork/data/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://edu.jcbfshr.com/geography/fieldwork/data/</guid>
          <description>Recording:
Local environmental survey Average house prices in given postcode Journey distance and means to nearest supermarket Noise at front door and nearest road (⩾B status) in dBA Distance to nearest green park</description>
        </item>
            
        
    </channel>
</rss>
